<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-04-17T10:39:18-04:00</updated><id>/</id><title type="html">Innovative Reel Technologies</title><subtitle>Keeping you in the fight longer, IRT provides quality products with patented technologies designed to help you to catch a variety of fish. Founded in 2007, IRT has created numerous products over the years and we listen to our loyal customers in order to continuously improve and make our reels the best in the industry.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Fall Fishing Frenzy: Choosing the Right Bait</title><link href="/blog/2017/09/20/fall-fishing-frenzy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fall Fishing Frenzy: Choosing the Right Bait" /><published>2017-09-20T11:47:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-20T11:47:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/09/20/fall-fishing-frenzy</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/09/20/fall-fishing-frenzy.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog--rivers-nature-fall-sky-sunrise-winter-mountains-autumn-landscapes-sunset.png&quot; alt=&quot;chinook-salmon-underwater-photo&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded float-right ml-4 mt-2 mb-3&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;
Now that the weather is cooling down, football should not be the only “F” word on your mind – the fishing is some of the best you can find. The nights are getting cooler, and the fish know what that means. To them, this signals the time to start eating for the long winter ahead. Let’s talk about what they are doing now. Bass are natural predators, they are going to follow baitfish. Most baitfish in lakes at this time will start heading to creeks and coves in order to feed-up, the bass will follow suit to feed on them. They will also start munching on crayfish more than normal now. One thing to pay close attention to is the color of the crayfish this time of year.  They begin molting for the fall, and will start to show an orange color. Crankbaits with the brown body, orange bottom work super in the fall.  I try and throw a lot of baits with some orange for this very reason. Top-water can also be electric this time of year. There is a new one on the market called a Whopper-Plopper, I recommend picking one up in (90) or (110) size in the “bone” color. It is a combination of a spook and buzzbait, just cast it out and reel it back. Tube baits and jigs also work great now, as the bass are looking to the bottom for crayfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panfish will begin eating as well; look in the ten to twelve foot range for them, as the sun comes up they will move closer to the bank. Some people like to use a bobber with a big leader. You can use a colorful jig head with a fat-head minnow, piece of worm, or a waxworm. They also become more aggressive again this time of year. Pay attention to trees that have fallen down in the water and rip-rap banks. They draw in bluegills and crappies this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catfish will continue their hunts at this time. Cutbait, nightcrawlers, chicken liver, and live bluegills are hard to beat. One thing to remember if you are fishing at night; don’t worry about casting out as far as you can, big cats often come in shallow searching for an easy meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog--chinook-salmon-underwater.png&quot; alt=&quot;chinook-salmon-underwater-photo&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded float-left mr-4 mb-3&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time of year also signals something very important to a certain species. The urge to spawn hits the salmon in Lake Erie and Ontario now. This is the time of the year that the rivers and tributaries are lined with anglers looking to hook into one. If this is your first time, please do not think you will go up and be sore from catching fish. Like anything else, those who do catch them at will have practiced their trade. They know how to read the water, and what stages the fish are at. Please do your due diligence and research the area you will be fishing, and talk to those that do go fishing. They are the ones that can help you out the most at this time. Pulaski is a popular destination, as is Oswego N.Y., this time of the year. Once the salmon stop in early November, people go for the steelhead and trout that follow them and then feast on their eggs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will say, if you have never tried it and said you always wanted to, please make sure you go, get some friends, family members and make a trip. It is a blast; along with the fish catching and camaraderie, you will make memories that last a lifetime. My family has been doing it now for going on fifteen years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time, get out there and enjoy this great fall weather!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Jeff&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Bass" /><category term="Panfish" /><category term="Catfish" /><category term="Bluegills" /><category term="Crappies" /><summary type="html">Now that the weather is cooling down, football should not be the only “F” word on your mind – the fishing is some of the best you can find. The nights are getting cooler, and the fish know what that means. To them, this signals the time to start eating for the long winter ahead. Let’s talk about what they are doing now. Bass are natural predators, they are going to follow baitfish. Most baitfish in lakes at this time will start heading to creeks and coves in order to feed-up, the bass will follow suit to feed on them. They will also start munching on crayfish more than normal now. One thing to pay close attention to is the color of the crayfish this time of year.  They begin molting for the fall, and will start to show an orange color. Crankbaits with the brown body, orange bottom work super in the fall.  I try and throw a lot of baits with some orange for this very reason. Top-water can also be electric this time of year. There is a new one on the market called a Whopper-Plopper, I recommend picking one up in (90) or (110) size in the “bone” color. It is a combination of a spook and buzzbait, just cast it out and reel it back. Tube baits and jigs also work great now, as the bass are looking to the bottom for crayfish.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRT 500 Review: Russ Dimauro</title><link href="/blog/2017/07/26/irt-500-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT 500 Review: Russ Dimauro" /><published>2017-07-26T12:10:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-26T12:10:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/07/26/irt-500-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/07/26/irt-500-review.html">&lt;p&gt;The IRT Reels team is dedicated to providing the best American made fishing reels out there! This means constant testing, improvements, and of course, listening to the professionals that are out casting every day. Here is a recent professional review of the IRT 500 Series Spinning Reel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello! My name is Russ Dimauro. I am a Senior Pro-Staff angler for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algagsfishinglures.com/&quot;&gt;Al Gag Lures.&lt;/a&gt; I became aware of IRT REELS though my friend Kil Song, at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jignpop.com/&quot;&gt;Black Hole U.S.A. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using the IRT500 to catch fish everyday for the last week. I’ve been catching loads of 30+ lb fish. The drag on the IRT500 works well very smooth and I’ve had it singing on several occasions! This reel is very comfortable to cast, lightweight and has great power. These fish have been caught using 4 oz jigs jigging the bottom with extreme current and it holds up excellent…lots of looks from other anglers and all comments have been positive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“This reel packs a punch!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;size-full wp-image-3803 aligncenter&quot; src=&quot;https://www.innovativereeltechnologies.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/RDimauro2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RDimauro2&quot; width=&quot;408&quot; height=&quot;544&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3806&quot; src=&quot;https://www.innovativereeltechnologies.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/RDimauro3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RDimauro3&quot; width=&quot;544&quot; height=&quot;408&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;aligncenter size-full wp-image-3807&quot; src=&quot;https://www.innovativereeltechnologies.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/07/RDimauro4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;RDimauro4&quot; width=&quot;408&quot; height=&quot;544&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IRT500 feels a bit on the small side for canal fishing. With a current of 5 knots, pulling big fish can be a chore, but so far so good. I feel the IRT600 should be a focus for the Cape Cod Canal market. Most popular size for canal 6 and up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russ&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11px;&quot;&gt;RUSSEL DIMAURO, Senior Pro Staff, Al Gag Lures&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">The IRT Reels team is dedicated to providing the best American made fishing reels out there! This means constant testing, improvements, and of course, listening to the professionals that are out casting every day. Here is a recent professional review of the IRT 500 Series Spinning Reel.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRT Q&amp;amp;A: Is cranking the bail to blame for knots in the line?</title><link href="/blog/2017/07/05/fall-fishing-frenzy.1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT Q&amp;A: Is cranking the bail to blame for knots in the line?" /><published>2017-07-05T09:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-05T09:40:00-04:00</updated><id>/blog/2017/07/05/fall-fishing-frenzy.1</id><content type="html" xml:base="/blog/2017/07/05/fall-fishing-frenzy.1.html">&lt;p&gt;At IRT Reels, we’re dedicated to getting the truth. Every so often, we hear questions raised from customers and other fishermen and -women. To answer these, we turn to professional anglers with years of experience. This question is answered by IRT Pro Staff member Scott H.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q:&lt;/strong&gt; I'm having some issues with knots in my line. I was told it could be caused by cranking the bail -- is this true?&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A:&lt;/strong&gt; Some knots in the line occur when the bail is cranked closed, but that isn’t the cause.  The best analogy I can think of is anti-lock brakes.  Some accidents occurred when people locked up their brakes - but the brake pedal wasn’t at fault.  The majority were caused by driving too fast, failing to drive defensively, and poor maintenance.  Anti-lock brakes help avoid some of those accidents, but they don’t prevent all of them because they don’t do anything about the underlying causes.  The real key is avoiding the situations that cause you to need to jam your brake pedal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am convinced that wind knots are caused, almost exclusively, by line twist and slack.  Cranking the bail closed can cause some momentary slack, especially when the line isn’t under the roller; and that can allow twist-loops to form.  But it’s the line twist that takes advantage of that slack to spin into a knot.  Manually closing the bail is focusing on when the knot occurs, and not why the knot occurs.  For guys fishing natural baits, manually closing the bail may stop most knots in the line from occurring.  But fishermen like me – who constantly cast lightweight lures into the wind – see wind knots occurring in many more ways.  For instance, if I am throwing a 1/4 oz. spoon, and I develop significant line twist, just lowering my rod tip can provide enough slack to allow a twist-loop to form.  If that gets reeled onto the spool, the next cast will create a knot.  The answer can’t be to quit throwing spoons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key to reducing knots in the line, I believe, is minimizing the things that cause the line twist, and periodic maintenance. The key for you, I believe, is education. There are a lot of traditions and myths about wind knots, and a tendency for a lot of fishermen to blame it on the reel. Manually closing the bail may be a good technique for certain fishing styles, but it won’t eliminate all wind knot problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are a list of things that either cause line twist, or contribute to wind knots in some way.  When people are having serious wind knot problems, I’ve found that several or even all of these conditions are present at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improper spooling. &lt;/strong&gt; Most people know that spooling line onto the reel in the direction opposite from the way it came off the manufacturer spool will create line twist.  A lot of people don't know that an over-filled  spool will exacerbate a wind knot problem tremendously.  Put a mark an eighth of an inch or so inside the outside lip to tell people &quot;stop filling here&quot;, and you will reduce the wind knot problem.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dry cranking a spinning reel.&lt;/strong&gt;  When you continue to turn the reel handle while a fish is taking drag, it automatically creates line twist.  But when a fish is sounding, or simply pulling just below the level to cause the drag to slip, a lot of novice fishermen, as well as some good fishermen, will crank the reel.  That added pressure will cause the drag to slip, and create the same line twist.  It's harder to recognize, because if they stop cranking they don't see any drag slippage.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Casting into the wind.&lt;/strong&gt;  Most people recognize that they get knots when casting into the wind, which is why they call them wind knots.  Casting into the wind can cause slack, but it can also create some of the line twist.  Most don't notice that a lot of baits, natural and artificial, spin when cast into the wind.  The wind knot occurs on a single cast, but it is often the 30+ casts before that created the line twist that led to the knot.  Note that a swivel cannot do much to help prevent line twist that occurs when the line is in mid-air, and in a somewhat slack condition.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rod and eye issues.&lt;/strong&gt;  The size, height, and placement of rod eyes have a big impact on how line plays off the spool of a spinning reel.  If line twist is present, and the line slaps on the eyes (especially the first two) or if it slaps on the rod itself, it slows the line down.  The line behind it continues to move, and creates slack.  The line bunches, and the twist takes over and forms a knot.  Some rods are built without considering eye placement, and some rod/reel combos simply cause more line slap than most.  Often you can take a reel that is producing knots in the line, transfer it as-is to another rod, and the problem goes away or becomes much less.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Swivels are also a part of the problem.&lt;/strong&gt;  Many people believe a swivel will prevent line twist, and they quit thinking about it.  But even good swivels will pick up debris like sand and grass.  Salt crystals form inside them as they dry.  They need to be rinsed, blown out, lubed, and manually rotated periodically or it is just like no swivel is present.  I have heard many people insist that they don't have line twist, because they always use a swivel.  And that leads them to conclude that something else must be causing their wind knot problems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A certain amount of twist is almost unavoidable.  Sooner or later, you really need to stretch the line out (many methods) and remove the twist that has built up.  How often depends a lot on fishing style.  It’s a pain, but so is changing the oil in your car.  The difference is that there are people who will change your oil for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know some people will disagree with the above.  But here is a test: whenever someone is having frequent problems with knots in the line, keep everything the same but change out the spool for one that is freshly and properly spooled with new line.  The wind knot problems will go away - at least for a while.  Doing several of the things listed above can cause line twist to develop pretty quickly.  But wind knots rarely occur with fresh, untwisted line, even in the wind.  The biggest caveat to that is that an over-filled reel, on top of a poorly-matched rod (eyes), can start causing wind knots right away.  That is because loose loops of line can spring off the reel, bunch up against the eyes, and turn into knots in the line almost instantly.  When cranking the bail closed is causing knots, the first place I would look is the amount of line on the spool.&lt;strong&gt;
&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scott&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 11px;&quot;&gt;SCOTT H., IRT Pro Staff&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">At IRT Reels, we’re dedicated to getting the truth. Every so often, we hear questions raised from customers and other fishermen and -women. To answer these, we turn to professional anglers with years of experience. This question is answered by IRT Pro Staff member Scott H.</summary></entry></feed>