<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="https://irtreels.com/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://irtreels.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://irtreels.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-11-19T11:58:00-05:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/</id><title type="html">IRTReels</title><subtitle>Keeping you in the fight longer, IRT provides quality products with patented technologies designed to help you to catch a variety of fish. Founded in 2007, IRT has created numerous products over the years and we listen to our loyal customers in order to continuously improve and make our reels the best in the industry.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">IRT’s Commitment to American-Made Excellence</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irts-customize-anything-and-everything.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT's Commitment to American-Made Excellence" /><published>2018-10-26T08:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T08:40:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irts-customize-anything-and-everything</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irts-customize-anything-and-everything.html">&lt;p&gt;Any angler will tell you that his reel is an extension of himself—why shouldn’t it be made that way? In a world where everything is mass-produced, finding a product that both performs beautifully and suits your personality is nearly impossible. Many brands will assume you want the same thing as every other customer, but we think you deserve a better experience. That’s why IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Reels allows you to customize almost every aspect of your reel. Whether you want the flair of a unique color scheme or the personal touch of a custom etching, we love working as a partner to build a piece of equipment that is just for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Etching.&lt;/b&gt; We know our customers take pride in their IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Reels, so we put our etching technology to use by adding custom printing and logo features to the manufacturing process. Whether you are looking for a spot for your charter boat’s brand, an etching of your initials, or a personalized gift for your favorite fisherman, IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; has you covered. Just take a look at this awesome etching we did for a customer this fall!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Colors.&lt;/b&gt; The vast majority of other reel brands don’t offer any deviance from the same color scheme across the board. We stand out from the crowd, and we know you do too. That’s why we give you the opportunity to select from a large list of color combinations. Your reel can match your favorite jersey, your boat’s detailing, or even your personal brand. Just check out some of our unique color combinations below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drag.&lt;/b&gt; Sometimes the fish that you’re targeting are just too much for the drag of the other guys to handle. That’s why we offer dual drag options that allow you to lay into that fish of a lifetime. If you want the single drag, we’ve got that for you too. Even our single drag reels outperform nearly all others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Grip.&lt;/b&gt; We offer two different grip options: the traditional grip and our patented Spin Power Grip™. The traditional grip is a classic design that many have come to love over the years. However, our Power Grip takes the ache out of the process. By taking the pressure off your fingers and allowing for a more comfortable resting position on the handle, this feature lets you fish for hours on end without feeling finger fatigue. See how these different grip options look on our 300 and 500 series reels below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The customization options from IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; are endless. If you want a red, silver, and blue 400 Dual Drag Power Grip with your initials etched into it, we can make that happen for you. Your IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; reel will be made with you in mind; as our customer, you deserve the right reel for your lifestyle. Don’t settle for the same, tired, baseline products—come get the reel you want for the life you live.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Foreman</name></author><summary type="html">Any angler will tell you that his reel is an extension of himself—why shouldn’t it be made that way? In a world where everything is mass-produced, finding a product that both performs beautifully and suits your personality is nearly impossible. Many brands will assume you want the same thing as every other customer, but we think you deserve a better experience. That’s why IRT® Reels allows you to customize almost every aspect of your reel. Whether you want the flair of a unique color scheme or the personal touch of a custom etching, we love working as a partner to build a piece of equipment that is just for you.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRT’s Commitment to American-Made Excellence</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irts-commitment-to-excellence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT's Commitment to American-Made Excellence" /><published>2018-10-26T08:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T08:40:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irts-commitment-to-excellence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irts-commitment-to-excellence.html">&lt;p&gt;PINE GROVE, PA – We all want American-made. Whether you are looking for a car, phone, or lawn mower, you’ll be hard-pressed to find a manufacturer committed to our level of domestic production. Sure, some produce parts or assemble their final product within our borders, but so few are able to do as much as we do right here in the good old U.S.A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Reels aren’t just assembled in America; we make almost every single part right here, and we’d never dream of sacrificing quality for cheaper materials. We take ownership of being American-made in the truest of senses. Our company is rooted in Pine Grove, Pennsylvania, and we aren’t going anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what does being an all-American company really mean? Beyond the parts and patents, what does it mean to commit to crafting these reels the American way? Our commitment to quality, reliability, and integrity is what separates IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; products from anything else in your arsenal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Quality:&lt;/b&gt; We know that no one wants to shell out their hard-earned money on a reel that is going to fall apart after a year of fishing. We know that nobody wants junk and we certainly don’t want to produce it. So why keep spending your money on products that aren’t able to keep up with you? IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Reels are built to last, and we’d put them up against any other reel in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Reliability:&lt;/b&gt; We know that no one wants to hook into the fish of a lifetime only to have a reel malfunction cost them the catch. Whether you’re casting for stripers, surf fishing for giant sand tigers, or fly fishing for bonefish, we know you want a reel you can count on. We also know that you want a reel that can get the job done over and over, in any condition, year after year, no matter where you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Integrity:&lt;/b&gt; We are fishermen, just like you. We take pride in crafting the most effective reels we possibly can and we won’t stand for mediocrity. If you’re looking for the bare minimum, you may want to look elsewhere — that’s just not in our DNA. If your reel ever needs a tune-up, just send it to our PA headquarters to keep enjoying that American-made quality for years to come. We know you want the same thing we do: the perfect fishing machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; makes more than just fishing reels. We promote lifestyles, passions, and excellence by keeping our sights on American quality, reliability, and integrity. Don’t accept less from anyone else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Innovative Reel Technologies&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an all American-made fishing reel, IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; prides itself in its patented fishing technology and methods of manufacturing in order to provide fishermen with the best reel on the market. With its customizable features and revolutionary Spin Power Grip™ technology, IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; is able to enhance any fishing experience that will provide memories for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Ben Foreman</name></author><summary type="html">PINE GROVE, PA – We all want American-made. Whether you are looking for a car, phone, or lawn mower, you’ll be hard-pressed to find a manufacturer committed to our level of domestic production. Sure, some produce parts or assemble their final product within our borders, but so few are able to do as much as we do right here in the good old U.S.A.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRT Named Best American Spinning Reel</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irt-named-best-spinning-reel.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT Named Best American Spinning Reel" /><published>2018-10-26T08:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-26T08:40:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irt-named-best-spinning-reel</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/10/26/irt-named-best-spinning-reel.html">&lt;p&gt;PINE GROVE, PA – All American Reviews &lt;a href=&quot;https://allamericanreviews.com/best-fishing-reels/&quot;&gt;recently published a post&lt;/a&gt; on the best fishing reels made right here in the United States and IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; was featured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the post, 10 reels were picked and IRT was the only spinning reel on the list. With IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;’s superior features standing out from the crowd, there were quite a few areas where IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; was highlighted. IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;’s customization capabilities, the flexibility of functioning well in both salt or freshwater, our aluminum machined spool, our reversible handle, and of course the strength and comfort behind our Spin Power Grip were a few mentioned positives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Greg Header was also quoted in the article: “IRT chooses to make its reels right here in the U.S., not only because we take pride in being American, but also because we care about creating American-made jobs. We want to use our grassroots beginnings to provide top-quality service to fellow Americans and bring customers the best products possible. With our patented technology and constant desire to improve through customer feedback, we truly aim to capture the American spirit. IRT takes pride in being the best that we can be, all while helping our customers and team achieve their full potential in the sport.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Innovative Reel Technologies&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an all American-made fishing reel, IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; prides itself in its patented fishing technology and methods of manufacturing in order to provide fishermen with the best reel on the market. With its customizable features and revolutionary Spin Power Grip™ technology, IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; is able to enhance any fishing experience that will provide memories for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Erin Collins</name></author><summary type="html">PINE GROVE, PA – All American Reviews recently published a post on the best fishing reels made right here in the United States and IRT® was featured.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRT Celebrates New Website Launch with Reel Giveaway</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/07/09/irt-celebrates-new-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT Celebrates New Website Launch with Reel Giveaway" /><published>2018-07-09T08:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-09T08:40:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/07/09/irt-celebrates-new-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/07/09/irt-celebrates-new-website.html">&lt;p&gt;PINE GROVE, PA – In celebration of its new website launch on July 9, 2018, &lt;a href=&quot;https://irtreels.com&quot;&gt;Innovative Reel Technologies&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; (IRTReels.com)&lt;/a&gt; announced a social media contest where they will be giving away one free IRT500DD fishing reel on Facebook or Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contest, which began on Wednesday, July 4, is all about sharing and promoting the IRT brand and run through the month of July. By liking the IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; Instagram page and using the hashtag #IRTReelAmerican on a fishing-related photo, readers will have their name entered once into the random drawing. If they like the IRT page on Facebook and comment on the post, their name will be added to the drawing a second time, increasing their chances of winning. The contest will last until Friday, July 27, and the winner will be announced Tuesday, July 31.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the contest, the new website will focus on bringing a better, more user-friendly experience to customers. With easier navigation, better design, and a more cohesive feel, IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; hopes to create a closer connection with users in order to continue to provide the highest quality customer and product service in the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information on IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; reels, visit the new site at &lt;a href=&quot;https://irtreels.com&quot;&gt;IRTReels.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Innovative Reel Technologies&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an all American-made fishing reel, IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; prides itself in its patented fishing technology and methods of manufacturing in order to provide fishermen with the best reel on the market. With its customizable features and revolutionary Spin Power Grip™ technology, IRT&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; is able to enhance any fishing experience that will provide memories for years to come.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Erin Collins</name></author><summary type="html">PINE GROVE, PA – In celebration of its new website launch on July 9, 2018, Innovative Reel Technologies® (IRTReels.com) announced a social media contest where they will be giving away one free IRT500DD fishing reel on Facebook or Instagram.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">/_#IRTReelAmerican July 2018 Giveaway Terms and Guidelines</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/07/03/irtreelamerican-july-2018-giveaway-tag.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="/_#IRTReelAmerican July 2018 Giveaway Terms and Guidelines" /><published>2018-07-03T08:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-07-03T08:40:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/07/03/irtreelamerican-july-2018-giveaway-tag</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/07/03/irtreelamerican-july-2018-giveaway-tag.html">&lt;p&gt;Overview of the competition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;i. No Purchase Necessary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. No purchase is necessary for any entrant to win and will not improve the entrant’s chances of winning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ii. Eligibility&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. The #IRTReelAmerican July 2018 Giveaway is open to any participants who are at least 18 years of age or older as of July 4, 2018. The shipping address for the prize must be within the United States. Employees of Innovative Reel Technologies® and its affiliates, as well as immediate family members of the employees, are not eligible to participate in the Giveaway. The reel Giveaway is subject to all applicable federal, state, and local laws and regulations. Void where prohibited.
&lt;strong&gt;iii. Prize&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. The winner of the random drawing will receive the exact IRT500 reel that is pictured in the graphic posts. No cash or other prize substitution shall be permitted and this prize is nontransferable. Any and all prize-related expenses, including without limitation any and all federal, state, and/or local taxes, shall be the sole responsibility of the winner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;iv. How to Enter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. Entries into the Giveaway are accepted via two social media platforms: Instagram and Facebook. Those entering the contest may participate in both social media outlets, increasing their chances of winning. Entries must follow the social media Terms and Conditions for both Facebook and Instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. Instagram: Entrants agree that they will post a fishing-related photo to Instagram using the #IRTReelAmerican hashtag, follow the @InnovativeReels Instagram page, and comment and tag a friend on the original post. All conditions must be met in order for the entrant’s name to be drawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;c. Facebook: Entrants agree that they will like and comment on the original Facebook Giveaway post and follow the IRTreels Facebook page. All conditions must be met in order for the entrant’s name to be drawn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;v. Winner Selection and Notification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. The winner will be selected via a random drawing under the supervision of IRT on Friday, July 27, 2018. The winner will be notified after he/she is deemed eligible via the aforementioned conditions and must claim their prize before Wednesday, July 31 when he/she will be announced on social media. IRT shall have no liability for the winner’s failure to receive notices via direct messages on either Instagram or Facebook. Any violation of these rules or lack of eligibility will have the winner disqualified from the campaign and another winner will be chosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vi. Agreement to Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. By participating in the #IRTReelAmerican Giveaway, you agree to be fully bound by these rules and acknowledge that you meet all eligibility requirements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;vii. Limitation of Liability&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. In no case shall Innovative Reel Technologies®, our directors, officers, employees, affiliates, agents, contractors, interns, suppliers, service providers or licensors be liable for any injury, loss, claim, or any direct, indirect, incidental, punitive, special, or consequential damages of any kind, including, without limitation lost profits, lost revenue, lost savings, loss of data, replacement costs, or any similar damages, whether based in contract, tort (including negligence), strict liability or otherwise, arising from your participation in the Giveaway or receipt of any product pursuant to it. In no case shall Innovative Reel Technologies® be liable for any other claim related in any way to your use of the service or any product, including, but not limited to, any errors or omissions in any content, or any loss or damage of any kind incurred as a result of the use of the Giveaway or its product.  Because some states or jurisdictions do not allow the exclusion or the limitation of liability for consequential or incidental damages, in such states or jurisdictions, our liability shall be limited to the maximum extent permitted by law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;b. All decisions of Innovative Reel Technologies® regarding the Giveaway shall be final. No participant shall have the right to contest or otherwise dispute any of its actions in managing the Giveaway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;viii. Social Media Disclaimers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. The #IRTReelAmerican Giveaway hosted by IRT is in no way sponsored, endorsed, administered, or associated with Facebook or Instagram. By entering this contest, entrants confirm that they are at least 18 years of age, and release Instagram and Facebook of responsibility, while agreeing to Instagram’s and Facebook’s terms of use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ix. Changes to Terms of Service&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. We reserve the right, at our sole discretion, to update, change or replace any part of these Terms of Service by posting updates and changes to our website. It is your responsibility to check our website periodically for changes. Your continued use of or access to our website or the Service following the posting of any changes to these Terms of Service constitutes acceptance of those changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;x. Contact Information&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a. Questions about the Terms of Service should be sent to us at reels@irtreels.com.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Erin Collins</name></author><summary type="html">Overview of the competition</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fish for Free Days in PA</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/05/23/fish-for-free-days-in-pa.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fish for Free Days in PA" /><published>2018-05-23T08:40:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-05-23T08:40:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/05/23/fish-for-free-days-in-pa</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/05/23/fish-for-free-days-in-pa.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog--pa-fish-and-boat.png&quot; alt=&quot;PA Fish and Boat Commission&quot; class=&quot;w-25 float-right ml-3 p-1&quot; /&gt;
On Sunday, May 27 and Wednesday, July 4, 2018 (Independence Day) Pennsylvania will be holding “Fish-for-Free Days” where no fishing license is required. This includes Lake Erie and Trout/Salmon permits. All other regulations are still in effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more information, please visit the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fishandboat.com/Fish/FishingRegulations/Pages/FishForFreeDay.aspx&quot;&gt;Pennsylvania Fish &amp;amp; Boat Commission&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nicholas Kline</name></author><summary type="html">On Sunday, May 27 and Wednesday, July 4, 2018 (Independence Day) Pennsylvania will be holding “Fish-for-Free Days” where no fishing license is required. This includes Lake Erie and Trout/Salmon permits. All other regulations are still in effect.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRT Reels Featured on WNEP</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/03/25/featured-on-wnep.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT Reels Featured on WNEP" /><published>2018-03-25T11:47:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-03-25T11:47:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/03/25/featured-on-wnep</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2018/03/25/featured-on-wnep.html">&lt;p&gt;Innovative Reel Technologies&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt; was featured today on &lt;a href=&quot;http://wnep.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;WNEP Channel 16 News&lt;/a&gt;. The feature includes a video of how IRT Reels are made as well as a feature on our sister company, Solar Innovations&lt;sup&gt;®&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wnep.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/Wnep_2008.png&quot; alt=&quot;WNEP Logo&quot; class=&quot;w-25 float-right  ml-4 mt-2 mb-3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wnep.com/2018/03/25/innovative-reel-technologies/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;IRT Reels Feature&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wnep.com/2018/03/25/innovative-reel-technologies-custom-made-reel-giveaway/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Innovative Reel Technologies Custom Made Reel Giveaway&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wnep.com/2018/03/22/power-to-save-recycling-in-the-greenhouse/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Power to Save: Recycling in the Greenhouse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wnep.com/2018/03/22/power-to-save-solar-innovations/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Power to Save: Solar Innovations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Nicholas Kline</name></author><summary type="html">Innovative Reel Technologies® was featured today on WNEP Channel 16 News. The feature includes a video of how IRT Reels are made as well as a feature on our sister company, Solar Innovations®.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRT Reel and Pro Staffer Featured in the Angler’s Almanac</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/12/15/on-the-water-anglers-almanac.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT Reel and Pro Staffer Featured in the Angler's Almanac" /><published>2017-12-15T10:47:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-12-15T10:47:00-05:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/12/15/on-the-water-anglers-almanac</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/12/15/on-the-water-anglers-almanac.html">&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href=&quot;/spinning-reels/400-series/&quot;&gt;IRT400 power grip reel&lt;/a&gt; made the cover of the January issue of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.onthewater.com/&quot;&gt;On The Water&lt;/a&gt; Magazine! It comes out next week, so mark your calendars and pick up a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;/media/d9d815b6&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/media-mention--angler's-almanac.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-footer=&quot;&amp;lt;div class='p-2 w-50'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class='align-self-start text-right m-0' style='display:block;width:100%;'&amp;gt;IRT's Pro Staffer, Joe Manansala, featured in the Angler's Almanac&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div class='p-2 d-flex  flex-column'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='mt-2 badge badge-secondary text-capitalize'&amp;gt;400 Series &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='mt-2 badge badge-secondary text-capitalize'&amp;gt;spinning&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div class='p-2'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class='lead m-0'&amp;gt;Joey Manansala&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&quot; data-gallery=&quot;irt-500-catches&quot; class=&quot;float-right w-50 pl-3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img data-src=&quot;/assets/images/media-mention--angler's-almanac.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded border&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations &lt;a href=&quot;/about/pro-staff/joe-manansala/&quot;&gt;Joey Manansala&lt;/a&gt; on your achievement!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Nicholas Kline</name></author><summary type="html">Our IRT400 power grip reel made the cover of the January issue of On The Water Magazine! It comes out next week, so mark your calendars and pick up a copy.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fall Fishing Frenzy: Choosing the Right Bait</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/09/20/fall-fishing-frenzy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fall Fishing Frenzy: Choosing the Right Bait" /><published>2017-09-20T11:47:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-09-20T11:47:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/09/20/fall-fishing-frenzy</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/09/20/fall-fishing-frenzy.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog--rivers-nature-fall-sky-sunrise-winter-mountains-autumn-landscapes-sunset.png&quot; alt=&quot;chinook-salmon-underwater-photo&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded float-right ml-4 mt-2 mb-3&quot; width=&quot;60%&quot; /&gt;
Now that the weather is cooling down, football should not be the only “F” word on your mind – the fishing is some of the best you can find. The nights are getting cooler, and the fish know what that means. To them, this signals the time to start eating for the long winter ahead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s talk about what they are doing now. Bass are natural predators, they are going to follow baitfish. Most baitfish in lakes at this time will start heading to creeks and coves in order to feed-up, the bass will follow suit to feed on them. They will also start munching on crayfish more than normal now. One thing to pay close attention to is the color of the crayfish this time of year.  They begin molting for the fall, and will start to show an orange color. Crankbaits with the brown body, orange bottom work super in the fall.  I try and throw a lot of baits with some orange for this very reason. Top-water can also be electric this time of year. There is a new one on the market called a Whopper-Plopper, I recommend picking one up in (90) or (110) size in the “bone” color. It is a combination of a spook and buzzbait, just cast it out and reel it back. Tube baits and jigs also work great now, as the bass are looking to the bottom for crayfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panfish will begin eating as well; look in the ten to twelve foot range for them, as the sun comes up they will move closer to the bank. Some people like to use a bobber with a big leader. You can use a colorful jig head with a fat-head minnow, piece of worm, or a waxworm. They also become more aggressive again this time of year. Pay attention to trees that have fallen down in the water and rip-rap banks. They draw in bluegills and crappies this time of year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Catfish will continue their hunts at this time. Cutbait, nightcrawlers, chicken liver, and live bluegills are hard to beat. One thing to remember if you are fishing at night; don’t worry about casting out as far as you can, big cats often come in shallow searching for an easy meal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog--chinook-salmon-underwater.png&quot; alt=&quot;chinook-salmon-underwater-photo&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded float-left mr-4 mb-3&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time of year also signals something very important to a certain species. The urge to spawn hits the salmon in Lake Erie and Ontario now. This is the time of the year that the rivers and tributaries are lined with anglers looking to hook into one. If this is your first time, please do not think you will go up and be sore from catching fish. Like anything else, those who do catch them at will have practiced their trade. They know how to read the water, and what stages the fish are at. Please do your due diligence and research the area you will be fishing, and talk to those that do go fishing. They are the ones that can help you out the most at this time. Pulaski is a popular destination, as is Oswego N.Y., this time of the year. Once the salmon stop in early November, people go for the steelhead and trout that follow them and then feast on their eggs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will say, if you have never tried it and said you always wanted to, please make sure you go, get some friends, family members and make a trip. It is a blast; along with the fish catching and camaraderie, you will make memories that last a lifetime. My family has been doing it now for going on fifteen years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until next time, get out there and enjoy this great fall weather!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;– Jeff&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jeff Cutler</name></author><summary type="html">Now that the weather is cooling down, football should not be the only “F” word on your mind – the fishing is some of the best you can find. The nights are getting cooler, and the fish know what that means. To them, this signals the time to start eating for the long winter ahead.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">IRT500 Review: Russ Dimauro</title><link href="https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/07/26/irt-500-review.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="IRT500 Review: Russ Dimauro" /><published>2017-07-26T12:10:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-07-26T12:10:00-04:00</updated><id>https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/07/26/irt-500-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://irtreels.com/blog/2017/07/26/irt-500-review.html">&lt;p&gt;The IRT Reels team is dedicated to providing the best American made fishing reels out there! This means constant testing, improvements, and of course, listening to the professionals that are out casting every day. Here is a recent professional review of the &lt;a href=&quot;/spinning-reels/500-series/&quot;&gt;IRT 500 Series Spinning Reel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello! My name is Russ Dimauro. I am a Senior Pro-Staff angler for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.algagsfishinglures.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Al Gag Lures&lt;/a&gt;. I became aware of IRT REELS though my friend Kil Song, at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.blackholeusa.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Black Hole U.S.A.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using the IRT500 to catch fish everyday for the last week. I’ve been catching loads of 30+ lb fish. The drag on the IRT500 works well very smooth and I’ve had it singing on several occasions! This reel is very comfortable to cast, lightweight and has great power. These fish have been caught using 4 oz jigs jigging the bottom with extreme current and it holds up excellent…lots of looks from other anglers and all comments have been positive!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“This reel packs a punch!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The IRT500 feels a bit on the small side for canal fishing. With a current of 5 knots, pulling big fish can be a chore, but so far so good. I feel the IRT600 should be a focus for the Cape Cod Canal market. Most popular size for canal 6 and up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;/media/ae383d50&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/photo-gallery/blog--RDimauro2.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-footer=&quot;&amp;lt;div class='p-2 d-flex  flex-column'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='mt-2 badge badge-secondary text-capitalize'&amp;gt;500 Series &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='mt-2 badge badge-secondary text-capitalize'&amp;gt;spinning&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div class='p-2'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class='lead m-0'&amp;gt;Russ Dimauro&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&quot; data-gallery=&quot;irt-500-catches&quot; class=&quot;float-left w-25 pr-3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img data-src=&quot;/assets/images/photo-gallery/blog--RDimauro2.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded border&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;/media/330d4c70&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/photo-gallery/blog--RDimauro3.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-footer=&quot;&amp;lt;div class='p-2 d-flex  flex-column'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='mt-2 badge badge-secondary text-capitalize'&amp;gt;500 Series &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='mt-2 badge badge-secondary text-capitalize'&amp;gt;spinning&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div class='p-2'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class='lead m-0'&amp;gt;Russ Dimauro&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&quot; data-gallery=&quot;irt-500-catches&quot; class=&quot;float-left w-25 pr-3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img data-src=&quot;/assets/images/photo-gallery/blog--RDimauro3.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded border&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a id=&quot;/media/a997effc&quot; href=&quot;/assets/images/photo-gallery/blog--RDimauro4.jpg&quot; data-toggle=&quot;lightbox&quot; data-footer=&quot;&amp;lt;div class='p-2 d-flex  flex-column'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='mt-2 badge badge-secondary text-capitalize'&amp;gt;500 Series &amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;span class='mt-2 badge badge-secondary text-capitalize'&amp;gt;spinning&amp;lt;/span&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&amp;lt;div class='p-2'&amp;gt;&amp;lt;p class='lead m-0'&amp;gt;Russ Dimauro&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;&quot; data-gallery=&quot;irt-500-catches&quot; class=&quot;float-left w-25 pr-3&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img data-src=&quot;/assets/images/photo-gallery/blog--RDimauro4.jpg&quot; class=&quot;img-fluid rounded border&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Russ Dimauro</name></author><summary type="html">The IRT Reels team is dedicated to providing the best American made fishing reels out there! This means constant testing, improvements, and of course, listening to the professionals that are out casting every day. Here is a recent professional review of the IRT 500 Series Spinning Reel.</summary></entry></feed>